# Christian

## Kane

Texas A&M Computer Science Student

### **Personal Info**

**Email** 

christiankane@tamu.edu

**Phone** 

832-364-7271

**Address** 

11902 Foxburo Dr Houston, TX 77065

GitHub

https://github.com/ChristianRossKane

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/christian-kane-845702177/

Website

tx.ag/ckane

#### **Skills**

Written and Verbal Communication

**Problem Solving** 

Programming

Mathematics

Agile Methodologies

**Public Speaking** 

## Languages/Frameworks

C++	****
Heroku	****
GitHub	****
Python	****
Java	****
PSQL	****
HTML/CSS	****
Ruby on Rails	****
React.js	****

I managed to complete my entire degree in 3 years with an above average GPA; while this did not allow for me to gather much experience through internships, it is a testament to how truly willing I am to *learn and work with diligence* under difficult constraints.

#### **Education**

2019-08 - present

Computer Science, Bachelor of Science

Texas A&M University, College Station (GPA, 3.647)

Expected to graduate May '22, 6 semesters total, with a BS in Computer Science and a Minor in Mathematics.

## **Work History**

2021-08

**Peer Teacher** 

- 2022-01

Texas A&M University, College Station, TX

Helped facilitate labs for Programming classes that I had excelled in, alongside holding Office Hours for the majority of core Undergraduate Computer Science classes.

## **Projects**

2021-08

**Team Leader** 

- 2021-12

The Aggie Nickwork Website

tx.ag/nickwork

Acted as the Team Leader in the development of the website used by The Aggie Nickwork, a student organization at Texas A&M. Used Ruby on Rails and Agile/Scrum methodologies to build the website over the course of a semester.

2021-01

**Backend Developer** 

- 2021-05

CAKAO Movies

cakao.herokuapp.com

Acted as the lead Backend Developer for a site called CAKAO movies; APIs were used to query large movie databases to (1) recommend films/shows to watch based on your watchlist and a movie search and (2) display showtimes for films in your area.

#### Courses

2021-01

**Design and Analysis of Algorithms** 

Senior elective in which we analyized and applied some advanced modern algorithms in computing, building upon and mastering basic data structures and algorithms.

Grade Earned: A

2021-08

**Software Engineering** 

Senior elective in which the class environment was meant to emulate a true software developmental environment using Agile methodologies in which a product was developed for a real client. First exposure to Ruby on Rails and CI/CD development using GitHub and a Heroku Pipeline.

Grade Earned: A